{
    "aboriginal_peoples":[
        {
            "question": "Who are the Aboriginal peoples in Canada?",
            "answers": "The Aboriginal peoples were the first people to live in Canada."
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the three main groups of Aboriginal peoples?",
            "answers": "The three main groups are the First Nations, the Inuit, and the Metis."
        },
        {
            "question": "The federal government placed Aboriginal children in residental schools to educate and assimilate them. How did the Aboriginal feel about the schools?",
            "answers": "The Aboriginal people did not welcome the schools, as Aboriginal language and cultural practices were prohibited."
        },
        {
            "question": "From whom are the Metis descended?",
            "answers": "The Metis are descended from early French and English fur traders and First Nations women."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which group of Aboriginal peoples makes up more than half of the population in the Northwest Territories and Nunavut?",
            "answers": "The Inuit make up more than half of the population of the Northwest Territories and Nunavut."
        },
        {
            "question": "Why are the Aboriginal peoples of Canada working toward self-government?",
            "answers": "The Aboriginal people of Canada are working toward self-government to keep their unique cultures and languages alive and to regain control over decisions that affect thier lives."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who have major responsibilities on First Nations (Aboriginal peoples) reserves?",
            "answers": "The major responsibilities on First Nations reserves are taken care by Band chiefs and councilors."
        },
        {
            "question": "How long have Aboriginal people lived in Canada?",
            "answers": "They have migrated from Asia for many thousands years ago."
        }],
    
    "history": [
        
        {
            "questions": "Where did the first European settlers in Canada come from?",
            "answer": "The first European settlers in Canada came from France."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Why did early explorers first come to Atlantic Canada?",
            "answer": "They early explorers first came to Atlantic Canada to fish and trade with Aboriginal peoples."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Who were the united Empire Loyalists?",
            "answer": "The united Emipre Loyalists were early settlers in the Atlantic region who left the United States during and after the American Revolution (1775-1783)."
        },
        {
            "questions": "When did settlers from france first established communities on the St.Lawrence River?",
            "answer": "Settlers from France first established communities on the St.Lawerence River in the early 1600s."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Who are the Acadians?",
            "answer": "The Acadians are the descendants of French colonists who began settling in what are now the maritime provinces in 1604."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What important trade did the Hudson Bay Company control?",
            "answer": "The Hudson Bay controlled the fur trade"
        },
        {
            "questions": "Whihc trade spread across Canada, making it important to the economy for over 300 years?",
            "answer": "The fur trade spread across Canada, making it important to the economy for over 300 years"
        },
        {
            "questions": "What form of transportation did Aboriginal peoples and fur traders use to create trading networks in North America?",
            "answer": "They used the Great Lakes as a waterway to create trading networks in North America."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Which countries fought in the war of 1812, and which country was defeated?",
            "answer": "The USA invaded Canada in the war of 1812, and was defeated by Canadians."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Who was the first leader of a responsible government in the Canadas in 1849?",
            "answer": "Sir Louis-Hippolyte La Fontaine, a champion of French language rights."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Who was Sir Sam Steele?",
            "answer": "Sir Sam Steele was a great frontier hero, Mounted Policeman, and soldier of the Queen."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Which Act granted, for the first time in Canada, legislative assemblies elected by the people?",
            "answer": "The Constitution Act of 1791 first granted the people the right to elect legislative assemblies."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What did the government do to make immigration to western Canada much easier?",
            "answer": "In the late 1800s the government built a railway across the Prairies to the Pacific coast that made immigration to western Canada much eaiser."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Who played an important part in building the Canadian Pacific Railway(CPR)?",
            "answer": "Chinese railroad workers played an important part in building the CPR."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What was the 'Head Tax'?",
            "answer": "The 'Head Tax' was a race-based entry fee charged for Chinese immigrants entering Canada."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Who was the General Sir Arthur Currie?",
            "answer": "General Sir Arthur Currie was Canada's greatest soldier in the First World War."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Approximately how many Canadians served in the First World War?",
            "answer": "More than 600,000 Canadians served in the First World War."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What was the Women's Suffrage Movement?",
            "answer": "The Women's Suffrage Movement was an organized effort by women to achieve the right to vote."
        },
        {
            "questions": "When is Remembrance Day celebrated?",
            "answer": "Remembrance Day is annually celebrated on November 11th."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What was the era of rapid change experienced by the province of Quebec in the 1960s called?",
            "answer": "The era of rapid change in 1960s was called 'The Quiet Revolution'."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Who are the Québécois?",
            "answer": "The Québécois are the people of Quebec."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the importance of D-Day in our history?",
            "answer": "Canada with democratic party attacked Normandy to liberate Europe from Nazi occupation"
        }],
    
    "government": [
        {
            "questions": " What does Confederation mean?",
            "answer": " On July 1, 1867, the provinces we know now as Ontario, Quebec, New Brunswick, and Nova Scotia joined together in Confederation to create the new country of Canada."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What is Canadian constitution?",
            "answer": " Canada's constitution is the system of laws and conventions by which our country governs itself."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Whay year was Confederation? ",
            "answer": "Confederation was in 1867."
        },
        {
            "questions": "When did the British North America Act come into effect?",
            "answer": "The British North America Act came into effect in 1867."
        },
        {
            "questions": " Why is the British North America Act important in Canadian history?",
            "answer": " British North America Act is important in Canadian history because it is the 1868 Act whihc officially created the new country of Canada by joing together the four provinces of Ontario, Quebec, New Brunswick and Nova Scotia legal in Confederation."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Which was the last province to join Canada?",
            "answer": "Newfoundland and Labrador was the last province to join Canada."
        },
        {
            "questions": "When is Canada Day and what does it celebrate?",
            "answer": "Canada Day is on July 1st and celebrates the anniversary of Confederation. "
        },
        {
            "questions": "Who was the first Prime Minister of Canada?",
            "answer": "Sir John A. Macdonald was the first Prime Minister of Canada."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Why is the Constituition Act of 1982 important to Canadian history?",
            "answer": "The Constituiton Act of 1982 allows us change our constitution without asking the British government for approval."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is Canada's Head of State?",
            "answer": "Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II is Canada's Head of State."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the Queen's representative in Canada?",
            "answer": "The Queen's representative in Canada is the Governor General of Canada."
        },
        {
            "question": "What do you call the Queen's representative in the provinces?",
            "answer": "The Queen's representative in the provinces is called the Lieutenant-Governor."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Canada's system of government called?",
            "answer": "Canada has a system of parliamentary government."
        },
        {
            "question": "What are three features of Canada's system government?",
            "answer": "Canada is a federal state, a parliamentary democracy, and a constitutional monarchy."
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the three parts of Parliament?",
            "answer": "The three parts of Parliament are: The Queen, The House of Commons and The Senate."
        },
        {
            "question": "What do you call a law before passed?",
            "answer": "A bill is a law before it is passed."
        },
        {
            "question": "How are Members of Parliament chosen?",
            "answer": "The people in each electoral district vote for a candidate of thier choice. Candidate with the most vote becomes MP for that electoral district."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who do Members of Parliament represent?",
            "answer": "An elected MP represents everyone who lives in his or her electoral district, even the people who did not vote for the MP."
        },
        {
            "question": "How does a bill become a law?",
            "answer": "To becoma a law, a bill must be approved by majorities in both the House of Commons and the Senate. Once a majority of MPs and Senators have approved the bill, the General gives final approval and the bill becomes law."
        },
        {
            "question": "What are three levels of government in Canada called?",
            "answer": "The three levels of government in Canada are: Federal, provincial/territorial and municipal(local)."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the government of Canada called?",
            "answer": "The government of Canada is called the federal government."
        }],
    
    "rights_and_responsibilities":[
        {
            "questions": "What part of the Constitution legally protects the basic rights and freedoms of all Canadians?",
            "answer": "The Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms."
        },
        {
            "questions": "When did the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms become part of the Canadian Constituition?",
            "answer": "The Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms become part of the Canadian Constituition in 1982."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Name two fundamental freedoms protected by the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms?",
            "answer": "Freedom of religion and Freedom of thought."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Name three legal rights protected by the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms?",
            "answer": "Right to life, Liberty and security of the person: the right to fair trail, and the right to protection against discrimination."
        },
        {
            "questions": "List three ways in which you can protect environment?",
            "answer": "Ways in which you can protect envirionment are as follows: Throwing waste in designated containers, recycling and re-using as many products as possible, and getting involved with a local group to protect our natural and cultural heritage."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Who has the right to apply for a Canadian passport?",
            "answer": "Canadian citizens have rights to apply for a Canadian passport."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What does equality under the law mean?",
            "answer": "It means that Canadian citizens have the right to protection against discrimination, in particular discrimination based on race, national or ethnic origin, colour, religion, sex age or mental or physical disability."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Name six responsibilities of Citizenship?",
            "answer": "Obeying Canada's laws, voting in elections, helping others in community, eliminating discrimination and injustice, caring and protecting Canada's heritage, and expressing opinions freely while respecting the rights and freedom of others."
        },
        {
            "questions": "List four rights Canadian citizens have?",
            "answer": "Right to enter and leave Canada freely, right to apply for Canadian passport, right to be educated in both official language, and the right to vote."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What will you promise when you take the Oath of Citizenship?",
            "answer": "I swear (or affirm) that i will be faithful and bear true allegiance to Her Majesty, Queen Elizabeth the Second, Queen of Canada, Her Heirs and Successors, and that i will faithfully observe the laws of Canada and fulfil my duties as a Canadian citizen "
        }],
    
    "geography":[
        {
            "question": "What is the population of Canada?",
            "answer": "Canada has a population of about 36 million."
        },
        {
            "question": "What three oceans border Canada?",
            "answer": "Canada is bordered by the Pacific Ocean on the west, the Atlantic Ocean on the east, and the Arctic on the north."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the capital city of Canada?",
            "answer": "Ottawa is the capital city of Canada."
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the five regions of Canada?",
            "answer": "The five regions of Canda are: The Atlantic Region, Central Canada, The Prairie Provinces, The West Coast, and the North."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which region covers more than one-third of Canada?",
            "answer": "Canada's northern region, comprised of Yukon Nunavut and the Northwest Territories."
        },
        {
            "question": "In which region do more than half of the people in Canada live?",
            "answer": "They live in southern parts of Quebec and Ontario."
        },
        {
            "question": "One-third of all Canadians live in Which province?",
            "answer": "One-third of all Canadians live in Ontario."
        },
        {
            "question": "Where are the Canadian Rockies?",
            "answer": "The Canadian Rockies form the border between Alberta and British Columbia."
        },
        {
            "question": "Where are the Great Lakes?",
            "answer": "The Great Lakes are in Ontario along the border between Canada and the USA."
        },
        {
            "question": "Where are the Parliament Buildings located?",
            "answer": "The Parliament Buildings are in Canada's capital city, Ottawa, Ontario."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country borders Canada on the south?",
            "answer": "The United States of America borders Canada on the south."
        },
        {
            "question": "What are Prairie provinces?",
            "answer": "Manitoba, Saskatchewan and Alberta are called Prairie provinces."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which province in Canada is the smallest in land size?",
            "answer": "Prince Edward Island is Canad's smallest province in land size."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a major river in Quebec?",
            "answer": "The St. Lawrence River is a major river in Quebec."
        },
        {
            "question":"On what date did Nunavut become a territory?",
            "answer": "Nunavut became a territory on April 1, 1999."
        }],
    
    "election":[
        {
            "question": "How many electoral districts are there in Canada?",
            "answer": "There are 338 electoral districts in Canada."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who has the right to vote in federal elections?",
            "answer": "A Canadian citizen, at least 18 years old, and on the list of electors."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is written on a federal election ballot?",
            "answer": "The ballot lists the names of the candidates in your electoral district in alphabetical order."
        },
        {
            "question": "what do you mark on a federal election ballot?",
            "answer": "You mark the ballot by writitng an 'X' in the circle beside the names of your chosen candidate."
        },
        {
            "question": "How is a government formed after an election?",
            "answer": "After an election, the party with the most elected representatives becomes the party in power."
        },
        {
            "question": "How is the Prime Minister chosen?",
            "answer": "The Prime Minister is the leader of the political party with the most elected Members of Parliament."
        },
        {
            "question": "When does an election have to be held according to the Constitution?",
            "answer": "According to the Constitution, an election must be held within five years of last election."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which party becomes the Official Opposition?",
            "answer": "The party with the second msot Members of Parliament becomes the Official Opposition."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the role of the opposition parties?",
            "answer": "The role of the opposition parties is to oppose or try to improve government proposals."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a voter information card?",
            "answer": "The voter information card confirms that your name is on the voters list and tells you when and where to vote."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who has the right to run as a candidate in federal elections?",
            "answer": "Any Canadian citizen who is at least 18 years old can run in a federal election."
        },
        {
            "question": "How are senators chosen?",
            "answer": "Senators are chosen by the Prime Minister and appointed by the Governor General."
        },
        {
            "question": "What should you do if you do not receive a voter information card telling you when and where to vote?",
            "answer": "Call your local elections office to make sure you are on the voters lists. if you do not have the number call Elections Canada, in Ottawa."
        },
        {
            "question": "After a federal election which party forms the new government?",
            "answer": "The party with the most elected representatives forms the new government."
        },
        {
            "question": "What does register of Electors contain?",
            "answer": "List of all Canadians citizens who are qualified to vote in federal elections and referendums."
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the secret ballot mean?",
            "answer": "It means that nobody has the right to insist that you tell them how you voted."
        }],
    
    "general":[
        {
            "questions": "What are the two official languages of Canada?",
            "answer": "English and French are two official languages."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Where does English and French have equal status in Canada?",
            "answer": "English and French have equal status regarding thier use in the Parliament of Canada, in federal courts, and in all federal institutions."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Where do most French speaking Canadians live?",
            "answer": "They live in the province of Quebec."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Which province has the most bilingual Canadians?",
            "answer": "Quebec. Over one-third of the population in Quebec speaks both French and English."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Which province is the only officailly bilingual province?",
            "answer": "New Brunswick is the only officailly bilingual province in Canada."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What are three main types of industries in Canada?",
            "answer": "The three main types of industries are: natural resources, manufacturing and service."
        },
        {
            "questions": "In what industry do most Canadians work?",
            "answer": "Over 70% of working Canadians have jobs in the service industry."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What country is Canada's largest trading partner?",
            "answer": "The United States of America."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Which region is known as the industrial and manufacturing heartland of Canada?",
            "answer": "Central Canada, which is made up of Ontario and Quebec."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What does the Canadian flag look like?",
            "answer": "The Canadian flag is whie with red border on each end and a red maple leaf in the centre."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What song is Canada's national anthem?",
            "answer": "Canada's national anthem is 'O Canada.'"
        },
        {
            "questions": "What is the first two line of Canada's national anthem?",
            "answer": "O Canada! Our home and native land! True patriot love in all thy sons command."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Where does the name 'Canada' come from?",
            "answer": "In the early 1500s, explorer Jacques Cartier used a First Nations word for village, 'Kanata' to refer to the whole country. European mapmakers later used 'Canada' as a name for all the land north of the St. Lawrence River."
        },
        {
            "questions": "Which animal is an official symbol of Canada?",
            "answer": "The beaver is an offical symbol of Canada."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What is the tower in the centre of the Parliament building called?",
            "answer": "The tower in the centre of the Parliament building is called 'Peace Tower'"
        },
        {
            "questions": "How many Canadians have been awarded the Victoria Cross, Canada's highest award of honour?",
            "answer": "96 Canadians have been awarded the Victoria Cross."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What is the largest religious affiliation in Canada?",
            "answer": "The largest religious affiliation in Canada is Roman Catholic."
        },
        {
            "questions": "What is Canada's national winter sport?",
            "answer": "Hockey is Canada's national winter sport."
        }]
    
}



